

### Denaro, Lino Garda

### Postdoctoral Fellow at National Taiwan University

dlinogarda@ntu.edu.tw

dlinogarda@tutanota.comweb: https://dlinogarda.com/

**wos**: AAM-9080-2020

ORCID

### Interests

Remote Sensing

Atmospheric Correction

Change Detection Analysis

Artificial Intelligence

Convolution Neural Network

# Overall Skills -

#### Programming:

MATLAB

Python

C#, CSS

#### Tools:

#### Remote Sensing Tools:

ENVI, SNAP

BEAM VISAT

Arc MAP

QGIS
Other Tools:

# Lino Garda Denaro, B.Eng., M.S., Ph.D.

# **Professional Experience**

Jul, 2022 – Present	Postdoctoral Fellow Department of Geography National Taiwan University (NTU)	Taipei, Taiwan
Feb, 2018 – Feb, 2022	Student Research Assistant Geo-Artificial Intelligence Laboratory Department of Geomatics National Cheng Kung University (NCKU)	Tainan, Taiwan
Feb, 2016 – Feb, 2018	Student Research Assistant Digital Geometry Laboratory Department of Geomatics National Cheng Kung University (NCKU)	Tainan, Taiwan
Sep, 2015 – Feb, 2016	Working in Government Institution Mapping and Development Department of Development Planning Agency of S	Surabaya, Indonesia Surabaya City
May, 2014 – Sep, 2014	Internship in Department of Remote Sensing Remote Sensing and Technology Center Lembaga Penerbangan dan Antariksa Nasional (L	Jakarta, Indonesia LAPAN)

### **Education**

2018 – 2022	Doctor of Philosophy	Tainan, Taiwan
	Department of Geomatics	
	National Cheng Kung University (NCKU)	
	<b>GPA:</b> 3.9	
2016 – 2018	Master of Science	Tainan, Taiwan
	Department of Geomatics	
	National Cheng Kung University (NCKU)	
	<b>GPA:</b> 3.9	
2011 – 2015	Bachelor of Engineering	Surabaya, Indonesia
	Department of Geomatics Engineering	
	Institute Technology of Sepuluh Nopember (ITS)	
	<b>GPA:</b> 3.38	
2008 – 2011	National High School	Kediri, Indonesia
	Natural Science Class 2	
	SMA Negeri 4	

### **Skills**

#### **Remote Sensing**

 Change Detection Analysis, Land Analysis, Ocean Color (Chl-a, Total Suspended Solid), Air Pollution (PM2.5,10), Ground Water Analysis, Hot-spot Area, Environmental Analysis

#### **Digital Image Processing**

 Histogram Processing, Image Filtering (Frequency and Spatial Domains using Fourier Transform), Morphological Image, Restoration and Reconstruction, Image Segmentation, Feature Extraction, and Image Pattern Classification

### **Programming**

• MATLAB, Python (Anaconda, PyCharm, Jupyter, Colab), C#, SQL, R, Java, JavaScript

#### **Machine Learning**

 Deep Learning (Dense Neural Network, Convolutional Neural Network), Water-Net, U-Net, Reinforcement Learning, Transfer Learning

#### **Computer Programs**

 Remote Sensing Software (BEAM Visat, SNAP, ENVI, Q-GIS, Arc-Map, etc), Video Editor (Adobe premier Pro), 3D Modelling (PIX 4D Mapper, AutoCAD, Agisoft Photoscan, Australis, Cloud Compare), 2D Design (Corel Draw, Photoshop), Office Applications, LaTeX

### Short Bio

During Lino's studies from 2014 - 2022, He has attended many local and international conferences among countries, such as Korea, Japan, Philippine, Taiwan, and Indonesia. He also has been publishing international papers and still going on. After graduated in Doctoral degree, He continue working as Postdoctoral Fellow in National Taiwan University (NTU) Taiwan.

### Metrics



# **Profiles**





# Languages

Indonesian (Mother Tongue)

English (TOEFL ITP:523, 2018)

Chinese (Intro. course, 2016-17)

### Personal

Lino was born in Batam, Indonesia. He received the B.Eng. degree in Department of Geomatics Engineering from Institute of Technology Sepuluh Nopember (ITS) Surabaya, Indonesia (2011-2015). Afterward, He got a scholarship in Taiwan to continue studying in the geomatics field for his master's degree (2016-2018) and followed by his doctoral degree (2018-2022). He graduated his Doctoral degree program in February 2022 with 6 papers and 1 paper in the submission process.

### Reviewer

- IEEE Journal of Selected Topics in Applied Earth Observations and Remote Sensing
- · IEEE Transaction on Geoscience and Remote Sensing
- · IEEE International Journal of Remote Sensing

### **Awards & Achievements**

2018 – 2022	Ph.D Distinguished Scholarship - NCKU, Taiwan
2018 – 2022	Ministry of Science and Technology (MOST) Scholarship, Taiwan
2019	Invited Speaker of PhilGeos Conference, Philippine
2017	Best Presenter of International Conferences of Indonesian Society for Remote Sensing (ICOIRS), Indonesia
2016 – 2018	M.Sc Distinguished Scholarship - NCKU, Taiwan
2016 – 2018	Ministry of Science and Technology (MOST) Scholarship, Taiwan
2015	Analyst Surveyor License (Indonesian Surveyors Association)
2013 – 2015	Van Deventer-Maas Scholarship (VDMS)

# **Organizations**

2019 – 2020	Secretary of Dewan Perwakilan Manasiswa, PPI Talwan
2018 – 2019	Department of Foreign Affair, PPI Tainan
2017 – 2018	Head Department Islamic Study of MSA, NCKU Taiwan
2016 – 2017	Head Department Islamic Study of MSA, NCKU Taiwan
2014 – 2015	Supervisor at Kost Quran SDM-IPTEK, Surabaya Indonesia
2012 – 2014	Department of Ristek FTSP ITS, Surabaya Indonesia

# **Publications**

Feb, 2020	IEEE Journal of Selected Topics in Applied Earth Observations and Remote Sensing Hybrid canonical correlation analysis and regression for radiometric normalization of cross- sensor satellite imagery
Jul, 2019	IGARSS 2019- IEEE International Geoscience and Remote Sensing Symposium Nonlinear relative radiometric normalization for Landsat 7 and Landsat 8 imagery
Mar, 2019	IEEE Geoscience and Remote Sensing Letters Pseudoinvariant feature selection using multitemporal MAD for optical satellite images
Feb, 2019	The International Archives of Photogrammetry, Remote Sensing and Spatial Information Sciences  Hybrid Canonical Correlation Analysis and Regression for Radiometric Normalization of Cross-Sensor Satellite Images
Nov, 2019	ISPRS Journal of Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing Spectral-consistent relative radiometric normalization for multitemporal Landsat 8 imagery
Aug, 2018	Journal of Applied Remote Sensing  Pseudoinvariant feature selection for cross-sensor optical satellite images

# **Conferences**

$21 - 24^{th}$ Nov 2021	Asian Conference on Remote Sensing (ACRS), Vietnam
$14-15^{th}\ \mathrm{Nov}\ \mathrm{2019}$	PhilGeos (GeoAdvences) Paper 1, Philippine
$16-17^{th}\ \mathrm{Nov}\ \mathrm{2019}$	PhilGeos (GeoAdvences) Paper 2, Philippine
$14 - 18^{th}$ Oct 2019	Asian Conference on Remote Sensing (ACRS), Korea
$17 - 19^{th} \; {\sf Apr} \; {\sf 2019}$	International Symposium on Remote Sensing (ISRS), Taiwan
$22-27^{th}$ Jul 2018	IEEE International Geoscience and Remote Sensing Symposium (IGARSS), Japan
$07-10^{th}$ Aug 2018	International conference of SG37, Taiwan
$31 - 01^{th} \; { m Oct} \; { m 2017}$	International Conference of Indonesia Society for Remote Sensing (ICOIRS), Indonesia
$05-07^{th}\ \mathrm{Des}\ \mathrm{2016}$	International Symposium on GNSS (ISGNSS), Taiwan
$12-15^{th}$ Jul 2016	International conference of SG36, Taiwan